IPA这种酒太有名了，好多人都知道
Because it's such a popular style most people know
或者他们自以为了解IPA的起源
or think they know of the origins of the IPA
这里是Beer By The Numbers频道的Ryan，字幕翻译给虫
Hey this is Ryan from Beer By The Numbers
今天带你了解印度淡色艾尔(IPA)这种酒的真实历史与其发展历程
and today we're diving into the true history and evolution of the IPA
关于IPA流传最广的说法是这样讲的
So the popular origin story of the IPA goes something like this...
18世纪晚期到19世纪早期
Back in the late 1700s and early 1800s
英国在印度有广大的殖民地
England held a large colonial presence in India
但士兵、水手和老百姓都超级想喝啤酒
But soldiers, sailors and civilians had a huge appetite for beer
问题是坐船去印度太慢了
Trouble was the voyage to India was long
按照当时的路线，船开到了之后
and by the time the ships made it there
普通的酒都快馊了
the traditional beers had spoiled
当然这是夸张的说法，但当时在伦敦比较流行的波特黑啤
Even when they didn't, the Dark Porter's that were popular at the time in London
也真不适合在天气炎热的印度引用
weren't quite the ticket in the hot climate of India
伦敦Bow酿酒厂的George Hodgson是当时第一位
George Hodgson of the Bow Brewery in London was the first person
想到解决办法的人
to come up with a solution to this problem
他开始酿造一种叫淡色艾尔的颜色更淡的啤酒
He began brewing a lighter style of beer known as Pale Ale
Hodgson发现酒精浓度高、酒花多可以在长途旅行中防止啤酒腐败
Hodgson realized that a high alcohol and hop levels would prevent spoilage on the long journey
他成功了
His process succeeded
之后他一直垄断印度的啤酒市场五十余年
and for about 50 years he held a virtual monopoly in the Indian market
所以……这故事错在哪呢？
So... what exactly is wrong with this story?
呃……就像很多有名的东西起源全归功于一人一样
Well... just like any story that gives all the credit to one person
事情远没有那么简单
it's never that simple
首先英国殖民者遇到的问题是真实存在的
It's certainly true that British exporters were experiencing problems
啤酒在去印度途中的确有保存问题
with beer making the journey to India
很多啤酒到达印度的时候根本没法喝
Much of the beer that arrived in India was not fit to drink
好多酒直接就倒海里了
and there were many accounts of beer being dumped into the sea
酒桶在海上遇到的这个问题根本没法避免
There was just no way to prevent the hardships a cask would experience while at sea
酒桶从英国出发时
When they first departed England
北大西洋的气候可以让啤酒保持在类似酒窖一样的问题
the North Atlantic kept the beer at a perfect cellar temperature
大概在50-55华氏度(10-12.8摄氏度)
between 50 and 55 degrees Fahrenheit
但当船开到赤道附近绕过非洲的时候这温度就保持不住了
But that didn't last as the ships neared the equator to pass around Africa
温暖的气候让酒桶里充满泡沫
where the warm seeds rock the cask to a foamy froth
酒桶能有80华氏度(26.7摄氏度)
and were a balmy 80 degrees
之后啤酒会在经过非洲好望角附近再次降温
Then the beer would be chilled again going around the Horn of Africa
然后到了殖民地以后又升温
before heating up again upon arrival to the colony
经过数十年的尝试与失败
Now through decades of trial and error
几个酿酒厂发现了一种减缓啤酒腐败的方法
a few breweries finally found a way to mitigate some spoilage
并加入了大量有抑制细菌功效的啤酒花
and add a lot of bacteria-killing hops
这虽然无法保证啤酒不会腐败，但至少酒更容易保鲜了
This was certainly no guarantee but it did make beer more likely to survive the journey
就这样，到了1760年，所有酿酒师都知晓了
So much so that by 1760, all Brewers were being advised
酿酒时加入大量酒花是非常重要的
that a large helping of hops was an absolute necessity
这条多放酒花的建议一传十十传百
This bit of advice about hops was being widely circulated
比之前Hodgson淡色艾尔的故事还要早25-30年
some 25 to 30 years prior to Hodgson Pale Ales
同时印度也在开发与波特、世涛口味相同的啤酒
In the meantime India was developing a great taste for the same porters and stouts
这些啤酒在英国很流行，但没那么多酒花
that were popular in London, although these were a bit hoppier
另外尽管Bow酿酒厂不是第一个把含酒花的淡色艾尔运到印度的
And although Bow Breweries wasn't the first hoppy Pale Ale to make it to India
但它的确是最有名的
it was certainly the most popular
但实际上，就算啤酒、加酒花的啤酒在印度很流行
But in reality, even though the beer and hoppy Pale Ales became quite popular in India
你会惊讶的发现它们在印度市场上、世界啤酒史上只是昙花一现
it's surprising to learn that the Indian market was never more than a blip
in the world of beer at the time
其巅峰时期印度一年只进口一万桶
At its height India was only receiving 10,000 barrels a year
只是来自北美的啤酒的六分之一
that was just one-sixth the amount received by North America
仅仅是来自英国最大一家酒厂的啤酒的十分之一
and just 1/10 of the largest single brewery in England
也就是十万桶
which alone turned out 100,000 barrels
如果说当时淡色艾尔在印度的进口量如此之小
Now based on the pretty small export market to India
那么IPA在精酿啤酒历史上只用一个脚注就够了
I think the IPA would have ended up a footnote in brewing history
但幸运的是，喜欢酒花的人太多了
But fortunately for hopheads everywhere
伯顿到伦敦的新铁路把淡色艾尔酿酒厂和伦敦市场连接起来
a new rail line between Burton and London links the Pale Ale breweries with the huge London market
很快本来打算在印度打的淡色艾尔广告
Soon Pale Ales advertised as ready for India
偶然的机会变成了在英国非常流行的啤酒
began being advertised as a popular special occasion beer
一家酿酒厂甚至说IPA是啤酒中的贵族
One brewery even touted IPAs as the beer of the gentry
这股商业冲击直接让IPA这一款啤酒流行开来
It was a commercial hit and this is when the style was born
而在印度，IPA从来没那么火过
IPAs never sold that well in India
但IPA名字中的India还是继续留在英国的商店标签上
but they became a standard bearer in the English market
从此，IPA加入精酿啤酒家族
As India Pale Ales have evolved
它往下，谱系分为两支，英国IPA和美国IPA
the family tree has split into two distinct categories: British and American IPAs
英国IPA是很适中的啤酒，酒精度约5%，中等酒花
British IPAs are modest beer, around 5% alcohol and only moderate hopping
而美国IPA比较强，酒精度在6-7%
American IPAs are stronger, generally between 6 and 7% alcohol
而且酒花味道和气味很浓烈
and showcase intense hop aromas and flavours
在19世纪，IPA的变化并不大
In the 19th century IPAs didn't change much
直到20世纪，一些世界级大新闻才改变了英国的啤酒风格
It wasn't until the 20th century that world events forced a change to the style in England
为了在一战中节省谷物
To save on grain during World War I
所有的英国啤酒都要求以低浓度酿造
all British beers were required to be brewed at a lower strength
这一规定永远改变了IPA
causing a permanent change to IPAs
在四十年代，风格依然是淡色艾尔
By the 1940s the style was about the same as a Pale Ale
但在很多酒厂，IPA酒精度却比普通淡色艾尔低
And in many breweries, the IPA was less alcoholic than their signature Pale Ale
在美国，禁酒令差点直接扼杀淡色艾尔的生产
In America prohibition nearly killed all ale production
也肯定摧毁了IPA在美国的流形之势
and certainly killed the popularity of the IPA in the US
但在九十年代，IPA在美国西海岸重新崛起
But the IPA found new life in the 1990s on the American West Coast
精酿啤酒酿酒师发现那里气候非常适合啤酒花生长
Craft brewers discovered the awesome hop growing climate
并开始放越来越多的啤酒花
and began using more and more hops
从此美国IPA死而复生
revising the all but dead style
很快西海岸IPA开始挑战加酒花啤酒的极限
Soon West Coast IPAs began pushing the envelope of what hoppy beer could be
到了今天，美国东北部的酿酒师
And today Brewers in the northeast of the US
又推出了新款的东北部IPA
are introducing another evolution to the style with the Northeast IPA
这些啤酒特点是颜色不透明，还带有很强的水果香味
These beers are characterized by their hazy color and strong fruit flavors
来搭配酒花的各种芬芳之感
to pair with all that hoppy goodness
最开始不起眼的IPA只是为了运往殖民地而发明
The humble IPA began as an export to a colony
之后从英国推广到北美，遍及全球
It circled the globe that spread from England to North America
这种啤酒差点在战争中消亡，却又变成精酿啤酒复兴的标识
It nearly died as a style and then became the symbol of the craft beer Renaissance
名字里带个印度，却从未在印度酿造过，这就是IPA
All while bearing the name of a country where it was never actually brewed